[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 3]
Regarding the matter of the Ming Hall,
[Zichen Hall]
you have already punished yourself by forfeiting your salary,
and all the guards in charge have been severely punished.
The immolator has died,
leaving only a lonely elder at home.
This matter
is now over.
You just got married yesterday.
For the next few days, the morning reports
will be excused.
Stay at home and spend some quality time with
your new bride.
Indeed.
I heard that the Grand Commander
spent the whole night investigating the Ming Hall arson case
and didn't return home.
The Grand Commander is working
loyally and diligently for you.
It's just a pity for his bride.
Your Majesty, you should give the Grand Commander
a few days off.
I'm afraid his loyalty and diligence are just a pretext;
he's actually deliberately neglecting his bride.
I was the one who arranged
the Grand Commander's marriage.
This morning, when I went to visit,
I found that the bride
had actually run away in anger.
The entire Shen family
has no idea
where she has gone.
Could it be that the Young Lady of the Yan family,
who had just married into the Grand Commander's Mansion,
has disappeared?
Lord Lai,
how can you say such nonsense
in front of the Grand Empress Dowager?
Your Majesty,
Lord Lai
is just worried for the Grand Commander.
I heard that
you plan to grant more power
to the Imperial Security Bureau.
This is a good thing.
However, the Grand Commander
can't even manage his household well,
so how could he wield
such significant power for you?
Mr. Shen,
what do you think?
Minister Zhang is absolutely correct.
How can one manage a country
if they can't even manage their own household?
I'll go back now
to comfort my wife
and handle the household matters.
I won't disappoint your expectations.
It's not like you were
investigating the case the whole night.
Why did you go to bed without washing up again?
Could it be that
the Grand Commander really didn't enter the bridal chamber?
This Yan Xing
is your niece, right?
Your Majesty,
[Jinzang, Musician]
Yan Xing
is the daughter of Ms. Jin from the Yan family.
And Ms. Jin
is my elder sister.
Don't worry.
This Shen Du kid
looks rebellious,
but he's actually quite disciplined.
He won't really do
anything out of line.
Yes.
[Ximing Temple]
I'll personally visit Liang's Mansion.
You,
what are you here for?
[Xu Xiangren, Head Constable]
Director Wu,
I heard there's a case here.
There is a case,
but does it have anything to do with you?
I heard that
yesterday you got into the bridal sedan
and married into the Grand Commander's Mansion.
Why are you out here
wearing your wedding dress today?
Did you
get thrown out?
You...
This woman always causes trouble
when she's on duty.
Sixth Lady is sharp-minded
and has learned a lot of investigative skills from Chen Wen,
the supervisor of the Prison Department.
She has been
a great help to us constables.
That's right.
Director Wu, Commander Xu,
I was too impatient.
I apologize for the rudeness.
I came here just to see
if there are any clues left
at the crime scene.
There are specialized personnel for investigating cases.
As a scribe,
you should just take care of the files.
Why are you trying to investigate cases?
Go, go. Go back to the Ministry of Justice
and change your clothes first.
Director Wu,
you just returned from the western suburbs, right?
Sir.
Look.
This blue flower on Director Wu's sleeve
is so beautiful.
Look, look.
Looks like Ms. Wu
has learned a new embroidery pattern.
It's a good thing
that young people
want to learn and progress.
If you want to investigate the case,
go in and take a closer look.
But don't interfere
with the constables doing their work.
Also,
don't meddle in affairs that aren't your business.
[Ximing Temple]
What's going on here?
Wu's wife can't embroider at all.
His lackey, Feng Gui,
has been frequently visiting the western suburbs lately.
His legs are always covered in mud from the western suburbs.
He even gave him a property deed.
It's highly likely
he's been keeping a mistress in the western suburbs.
Mis...
Let's go.
I'm a scribe from the Ministry of Justice.
May I take a look?
If you're not afraid, go ahead.
Sir,
did you notice
anything unusual before?
I haven't found anything yet.
I heard that
when they were just dug up,
they were still tightly holding each other.
Both of them
had their hearts removed
and died from blood loss.
The woman's face was slashed,
but her expression is peaceful.
The man's body is intact,
but his skin has turned black.
From the scratches and bloodstains,
it seems the cuts were made after death.
In such weather,
their bodies actually
don't give off any foul odor;
instead, there's a fragrance
of mixed medicinal herbs.
Xing,
are you out of your mind?
How could a body have a fragrance?
Sixth Lady.
What you said is spot on.
This morning, a young monk
found the bodies
while digging for bamboo shoots
in the bamboo forest outside the temple.
We've confirmed that the man
is Liang Chenzhong, the eldest legitimate son of Mr. Liang,
the former Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Works,
and the woman
is Kuang Zhanxin, an entertainer from Pingkang House.
Could this be a case
of love suicide?
No.
The man's skin has turned black.
Have you found out what poison he was exposed to?
-The poison is...
-Zhong!
Zhong!
-My son!
-Madam Liang, my condolences.
Please, try to compose yourself.
Zhong!
[Liang Chenyu]
You were just talking about poisoning?
The poison your son was exposed to
is Water Dropwort.
[Madam Liang]
We, the constables
of the Ministry of Justice,
[Liang Jiren]
will definitely
get to the bottom of your son's death.
What's the use of that?
Liang.
Please forgive us.
I'm terribly sorry.
Mr. Liang, take care.
Are we still investigating?
Ximing Temple is a royal temple sanctioned by the emperor.
All the prominent officials and aristocrats in Xiang'an
come here
to pay their respects.
Now that such a thing has happened,
we naturally need to provide an explanation.
Yes, yes, yes.
After Madam Liang made a fuss,
my mind is in a mess.
Quickly investigate the case
and close it as soon as possible.
Lu Chuichui.
Yes.
Go.
Send the information we've gathered
back to the Ministry of Justice for archiving.
I heard that the abbot of Ximing Temple
has some fine tea hidden.
Let's go.
Let's mooch some of his tea.
He's going to drink tea?
How dare he drink tea?
Wu Taiming.
Sounds like "no peace."
All he does is throw his weight around.
What a bastard.
Xing,
you've been staring at the corpses for so long.
When you're done,
let's go together.
Wu Taiming
is going to enjoy tea.
We shouldn't shortchange ourselves either.
I'll take you to Furong Garden to watch a new play
and have some good tea.
Chuichui, you go back first.
I want to go to the corpse pit
and take a closer look.
Go ahead.
Alright.
I'm leaving.
Water Dropwort?
It seems you still
haven't remembered what I said.
How dare I?
Why did you come here
instead of staying in Shen's Mansion?
Although I've married into the Shen family,
I'm still a scribe at the Ministry of Justice.
A murder has occurred here.
How could I not come?
You're just a scribe
with no rank at the Ministry of Justice.
How come you've taken on
the responsibility of a coroner?
And I've never heard that
the Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau
needs to personally put out fires.
For that, you even worked through the night
and missed the auspicious time.
Grand Commander,
I just asked the constables for the results of the investigation.
There's very little blood in the pit,
mostly corpse fluids.
Mr. Liang and Ms. Kuang
were likely transported here
after their blood
had almost dried up.
But there aren't any vehicle tracks nearby,
only plenty of footprints.
There are countless pilgrims who come here.
Even Princess Ying is a regular visitor.
What can you deduce from the footprints?
What about the shovel marks in the pit?
Can you determine when they were made?
It should have been some time ago,
but the coroner said it was hard to determine the exact time.
It was the 15th of April.
How do you know?
The edge of the pit is thin at the top and thick at the bottom,
with sharp drop-offs and rounded edges.
The murderer or the accomplice
must have used
a commonly used round-tipped shovel.
The soil at the bottom is compacted,
with the center being dense
and the surrounding soil loose.
This is typical of soil after rainfall.
Today is the 8th of May.
The last time it rained
was the 15th of April.
Here.
I picked them up
when I came out this morning.
When I get back, I'll ask the old housekeeper
which shop he bought such sweet preserved fruit
from.
Here.
Soil conditions can be quite variable.
Your findings might not be reliable.
Look here.
About 3 feet and 8 inches above the ground,
there's a soil mark.
It was caused by mud splashing.
The bamboo in Ximing Temple is yellow groove bamboo.
One day after rain,
it can grow 1 to 2 inches.
The splash mark is directly facing the corpse pit,
which is thick at the bottom and thin at the top.
It must have been made that day.
Chen Wen taught you these things too?
Honey,
I'm very attentive to you
and have investigated you thoroughly.
My Master once told me
that capturing the murderers
and bringing them to trial
is the responsibility of the Ministry of Justice.
Therefore, making every effort to solve cases
is the duty of every member
of the Ministry of Justice.
You're just a scribe
with no rank.
The responsibility of the Ministry of Justice
has nothing to do with you.
-I…
-We just got married yesterday.
Today, you should come back with me to Shen's Mansion
and learn what a wife should do.
The Grand Commander's Mansion hastily arranged the wedding.
Now, everyone in Xiang'an knows
that you don't like me.
And coincidentally,
I'm not
fond of you either.
So from now on,
we'll each go our separate ways
and not interfere with each other.
You don't need to worry about
what responsibility I should take on.
It seems that today,
I have to worry about it
after all.
Shen Du!
Let go of me!
Put me down.
Shen Du! Shen Du!
What are you doing?
Ximing Temple indeed deserves its reputation.
There's no such good tea
in the government office.
I'm unfortunate
to have married a wife
who is devoted to her official duties.
I can only take her back home for some intimacy.
Put me down now!
The scenery is not bad.
Shen Du, what are you doing?
Put me down!
Honey, you should be more obedient.
Otherwise,
I might have to show our affection in public.
That's...
That's... that Yan Xing?
And the other one on the horse is...
Grand Commander Shen.
Isn't it said that White Ghost
put a knife to Mrs. Shen's neck
to threaten her on their wedding day?
Looks like it's just a rumor.
Now,
you are already
Mrs. Shen in the eyes of everyone.
Since you're in the game,
there's no option
to leave unscathed.
A monkey in human attire.
Grand Commander, are you putting on this act
to gain a reputation
as a good husband?
We are newlyweds.
Naturally, we should stick together.
Today,
I will make sure you
and the people behind you are satisfied.
The Imperial Security Bureau is busy every day.
You must have
many affairs
to handle
for the Grand Empress Dowager.
I'm afraid taking me along
would be inconvenient for you.
Honey, are you dead or disabled?
Grand Commander!
Since you're neither dead nor disabled,
there's no inconvenience at all.
There's a letter from the palace.
Solve the Liang family murder case at Ximing Temple quickly
[Imperial Decree from the Grand Empress Dowager: Solve the Liang family murder case at Ximing Temple quickly]
and protect Liang Chenyu from the second branch of the Liang family.
No delays.
We need to go somewhere.
Where?
Liang's Mansion in the Fengyue District.
[Liang's Mansion]
What's the situation?
He's not investigating the case,
but I need to investigate.
I can't keep following him around like this.
Grand Commander,
our Third Young Master is waiting for you in the study.
Grand Commander.
If you don't call me Honey,
once we leave Liang's Mansion,
you can kiss your tongue goodbye.
Honey.
I'm listening.
We don't work in the same section.
You need to talk to the head of the second branch.
It's not very appropriate for me to follow.
How about
I wait for you outside?
I just want to go for a walk.
Alright.
Jing Lin.
Follow her.
Yes.
Grand Commander, this way please.
I haven't slept all night.
I need to take a nap here.
Go over there and keep watch for me.
Alright then.
Since you Imperial Guards
can even watch
the Grand Commander's wife sleep,
why should I be shy?
You can keep watch yourself.
Mrs. Shen?
Why are you here?
This is for you.
It's very sweet.
I heard that after the Liang family was split,
they built a wall between them.
The trees around here seem to
have been moved here later.
Logically speaking,
pear, mulberry, and locust trees
aren't considered auspicious choices.
The Second Madam had people move them here
when she went mad.
These trees symbolize
separation, subtle criticism, and a guilty conscience.
These two brothers must hold deep-seated grudges against each other.
Could it be true,
as the rumors say,
that the Water Dropwort poison that Liang Chenman,
the Second Madam's son, was poisoned with
came from the first branch of his uncle's family?
Don't say that!
However,
the Second Madam went mad
after the death of the Second Young Master.
Ever since,
the door between
the first and second branches
has never been opened again.
Madam!
Mrs. Shen, what are you doing?
I'm hiding from White...
I'm hiding from my husband.
Well...
Since I married him yesterday,
my husband
hasn't been willing to leave my side for a moment.
He sent someone
to follow me closely everywhere.
I really need a break.
Is White...
Is the Grand Commander that clingy?
So that's how it is.
I was actually wondering about it.
Though the Grand Commander often comes here,
this is the first time
he's brought a lady into the mansion.
My husband
is actually so close with the Liang family?
The Grand Commander and our Third Young Master
are very close.
He often brings
medicinal herbs
to the Second Madam Liang.
Something happened in the Second Madam's courtyard again!
Let's go!
It's the Second Madam's courtyard!
The Grand Empress Dowager has issued an order,
saying the design drawings for the improvements to the crossbows
must be completed on schedule
without delay.
But right now,
how can I focus on drawing?
Your brother Liang Chenzhong's case
is being investigated by the Imperial Security Bureau.
You can rest assured.
It's...
Your family has served in the Ministry of Works for generations
and is skilled in designing bows and mechanics.
Most of our country's military crossbow equipment
was designed by your grandfather.
That's how we've earned our reputation on the battlefield.
For this generation,
only you can
be entrusted with such an important responsibility.
The Grand Empress Dowager has always valued talent.
You just need to focus on completing
the task assigned to you.
Just like before,
every time my father picked up his brush,
your father would immediately turn and leave.
Before my father passed away,
he could never forget
what happened that year.
Shen Bingzhu
[Memorial Tablet of Shen Bingzhu, My Father]
deserves to be executed for his crime.
There's no need to mention it again.
Don't worry.
I won't repeat
that person's mistakes.
Man.
Water Dropwort?
Don't touch my Man!
Man.
[Second Madam Liang]
Don't touch my Man!
Help!
Grand Commander, over there!
Shen Du,
You're so vicious.
You can't drive me away,
so you're trying to take this opportunity
to let me drown here!
Help!
Here.
Clean yourself up.
Quickly escort the Grand Commander's wife
to bathe and get changed.
I apologize for any offense caused today.
Grand Commander, Madam, please forgive us.
It's alright.
Tell your Third Young Master
to focus on his task and not worry.
Yes.
I'll take my leave now.
If I hadn't seen it with my own eyes,
who would have thought that
White Ghost,
who strikes fear into people's hearts,
would actually be such a considerate husband?
He treats others coldly,
but in reality, he's a romantic husband in front of his wife.
What exactly did you say
to those maids?
I was just playing along with your act
of being a good husband.
Maids from such prestigious households
are the most effective at spreading rumors.
Why did you save me?
If I had drowned,
it would have been an accidental death.
You wouldn't have to find a way
to get rid of me.
Wouldn't that have been killing two birds with one stone?
You are still
useful to me.
[Shen's Mansion]
Madam,
I have arranged
your belongings.
You will sleep here tonight.
Didn't the Master say
that the main chamber shouldn't be used as a bridal chamber
because it might bring bloodshed?
The Master has already resolved it.
You can stay here with peace of mind.
I think
the feng shui in the west wing is better.
It brings me more good fortune.
I'll go back and stay there.
Stop.
You don't have a choice.
If you want to die,
you can leave Shen's Mansion.
Fine, I'll stay.
I'm not afraid of it.
Bloodshed?
We'll see who will bleed first.
Madam,
your husband hasn't started eating yet.
So what?
I'm hungry.
It was Second Madam of the Liang family
who caused me to fall into the water today.
Her son died years ago
from the poison
of Water Dropwort.
But now she treats that pot of poisonous plant
like her own child,
calling it Man.
Now, Liang Chenzhong from the first branch
has also been poisoned by Water Dropwort.
What a coincidence, huh?
Don't talk while eating.
I've finished eating.
Do you also think
Liang Chenzhong's death
is revenge from the second branch of the Liang family?
Grand Commander.
Send it away.
Yes.
Why did he leave in such a hurry?
Couldn't he at least finish his meal?
You talk too much.
You're controlling when I eat or drink.
Are you going to control whether I talk or blink as well?
Remember,
in Shen's Mansion,
it's better for you to choose
to be blind and deaf.
The Liang Chenzhong case
has been handed over to the Imperial Security Bureau.
The Ministry of Justice is in charge of this case.
Honey, aren't you very clever?
The Grand Empress Dowager has transferred
this case from the Ministry of Justice
to the Imperial Security Bureau.
Don't you understand
her intention behind it?
The Grand Empress Dowager wants to settle it quietly.
This is because the Liang family holds an important position in the Ministry of Works.
The designs for the crossbows of our country
all come from the Liang family.
Liang Chenman from the second branch died unexpectedly,
and now Liang Chenzhong has suddenly died.
If this family grudge involves
the Third Young Master,
it will inevitably affect the continuation
of the Liang family's legacy in technology.
You're not completely stupid after all.
The second branch of the Liang family can't be imprisoned.
Unless...
you want to oppose the Grand Empress Dowager.
Or is this...
Zhang Xingwei's intention?
I don't work for Minister Zhang.
You left the scroll in the room deliberately
to test me.
You should thank your cleverness.
Otherwise,
you would have already died by now.
Actually, I didn't even need to open it
to guess that
it was the crossbow design inside.
Why are you laughing?
I'm laughing at you.
You, as the Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau,
without verifying,
have already concluded that the murderer is from the second branch of the Liang family.
But the truth may not be so.
The second branch of the Liang family has a grudge against Liang Chenzhong,
but the murderer
only slashed the singer's face
deeply enough to expose the bone.
I've told you,
you don't need to investigate this case.
What if I insist?
You can either remain silent as a living person
or become
a dead one who can't speak.
Grand Commander,
how about we have a bet?
You really aren't afraid I'll kill you.
Of course I'm afraid.
But you also said
that I'm still useful to you.
What?
Are you afraid of losing the bet?
How do we bet?
Let me investigate.
If the murderer
really is Liang Chenyu, the Third Young Master of the Liang family,
you win.
By then, I'll voluntarily ask to be dismissed as your wife,
and my life
will be in your hands.
You really think
your life is too long, don't you?
But if I find the real murderer,
three months later,
we'll divorce.
It's not just you who doesn't want this marriage;
I don't want it either.
We have no grudge against each other.
I don't ask for eternal happiness.
I just want a peaceful separation.
Fine.
No matter what,
I have to get through these three months.
Once the female official examination is over,
the assignment for external duty
should be settled.
It would be a bit inappropriate for me
to stay in the main chamber, wouldn't it?
Just stay here.
Our marriage was bestowed
by the Grand Empress Dowager.
To everyone,
we must appear deeply in love,
inseparable.
If you can't do that…
I will lose my head.
Alright, I got it.
You know what?
I feel like
I really fit in with this main chamber.
Well then, if that's the case,
I want all the treatment that comes with
being the Madam of the household.
To put on a show, you have to do the whole thing.
So I'll sleep there.
Where will you sleep?
Didn't you say so?
Whole,
thing.
We're newlyweds,
inseparable.
We can only sleep together now.
You're in my bed with your outer clothes on?
I've always been like this at home.
Honey, if you're not used to it,
then you'll have to get used to it.
Honey, you're right.
I should indeed get used to it.
You're lying on my hair.
You know what?
These preserved fruits in Shen's Mansion are so delicious.
I can't get enough of them.
Not bad.
Would you like one?
You...
Uncle Zhong!
Change them.
Change them all!
The lights are too bright.
Can we turn them off?
No.
How can I sleep with them so bright?
You don't have to sleep.
Chi,
how have you been in Jiangnan?
Recently, I solved
a wife murder case.
The victim didn't commit suicide.
Let me restore
the scene for you.
Yuanniang.
After you strangled Wang Yuanniang,
you looped the corpse's neck,
dragged it to the beam,
then hung the other end of the rope
on the beam
and pulled hard to hang her.
All of this
left marks on the beam.
So,
there are two strangulation marks
on her neck.
One is black, pointing backwards,
and the other is brown, pointing upwards.
You still have the marks
from the hemp rope on your hands.
She was strangled to death by you.
Miss Yan,
Ms. She has already confessed
that she assisted Cheng Xian
in the murder of his wife.
This small garment was embroidered by Yuanniang, wasn't it?
According to the coroner's examination,
Wang Yuanniang
was two months pregnant.
You're trying to deceive me!
Even if she was pregnant,
so what?
You were resentful about marrying into her family
and killed Wang Yuanniang in anger.
But you didn't know
that she had been deeply in love with you
and had already planned to have the child
take your surname after birth.
The embroidery on this small garment
is the surname Cheng.
[Cheng]
You always blame Wang Yuanniang's maternal family
for oppressing you,
but you know the truth better than anyone.
Yuanniang,
I'm sorry, Yuanniang.
Yuanniang...
But there's
a strange needle wound
on the deceased's body.
[There is a triangular needle wound on Yuanniang's body]
The coroner hasn't determined its origin yet.
Recently, a lot of changes
have happened to me.
Five o'clock.
It's 3 AM now.